<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Transitional//EN"
        "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-transitional.dtd">
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xml:lang="en" lang="en">
<head>
	<meta http-equiv="content-type" content="text/html; charset=utf-8" />
	<title>Referrers</title>
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="refer.css" type="text/css" />
	<meta name="robots" content="noindex" />
</head>
	<body>			
		<table align="center" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"><tr><td colspan="4" class="noliner"><a href="index.php">refresh</a> | glimpse: <a href="index.php?glimpse=1">24hr</a>  <a href="index.php?glimpse=2">48hr</a>  <a href="index.php?glimpse=3">72hr</a>  <a href="index.php?glimpse=7">1week</a>   | <a href="?queries=1">queries</a> | <a href="?format=help">help</a></td></tr><tr><td width="500"><p>RSS feed for <a href="http://www.zeldman.com/">Jeffrey Zeldman Presents: The Daily Report</a></p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.zeldman.com/daily/0104d.shtml">ALA 166</a></p><p>In this week's issue of A List Apart, for people who make websites: FAUX COLUMNS by Dan Cederholm. (Multi-column layouts can run into trouble in CSS. Here's a simple solution.) ELASTIC DESIGN by Patrick Griffiths. (Not quite liquid design, yet not fixed-width either, Elastic Design combines the strengths of both.)</p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.zeldman.com/daily/0104c.shtml">Wish we'd designed that: Redlabor of love</a></p><p>Sometimes it all comes together. (Plus: Papa's got a brand new Airbag; Cloninger on archiving, ephemera, and analog distortion; more.)</p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.zeldman.com/daily/0104b.shtml#linkydoodle">Linky Doodle Do</a></p><p>Lovely, inspiring sites added to our reorganized Externals department.</p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.zeldman.com/daily/0104b.shtml#fontifier">Your Handwriting on Your Computer</a></p><p>New free service converts your handwriting to TrueType fonts.</p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.zeldman.com/daily/0104b.shtml#megareference">Web Design Mega Reference</a></p><p>Over 30,000 organized links, with an emphasis on web standards and accessibility.</p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.zeldman.com/daily/0104b.shtml#pvcomics">PV Comics launch</a></p><p>Free comics in a switchable high/low-bandwidth layout using Stuart Robertson's CSS image map technique (ALA issue 166).</p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.zeldman.com/daily/0104b.shtml#checkthese">Big Eyed Beans From Venus</a></p><p>Indie sites, fashion sites, blogger awards, book review, affordable stock photos, more.</p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.zeldman.com/daily/0104a.shtml">Goodies for you</a></p><p>Favelets and Linky-poos from us to you.</p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.zeldman.com/daily/0104a.shtml#woodies">Wood that will not bend</a></p><p>Resonant chunks of pop culture, plus vaults, dailys, a panorama, and Sir Tim to you.</p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.zeldman.com/daily/1203k.shtml">Le Redesign, C'est Fini!</a></p><p>Redesign: done. Design goals explained. Last browser bugs squashed.</p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.zeldman.com/daily/1203i.shtml#onion">Win the Onion</a></p><p>Blogstakes presents your chance to win The Onion Platinum Prestige Encore Gold Premium Collector's edition. It's as easy as typing a link. Previous Blogstakes included a free year of Browsercam and the fabulous Clip-n-Seal.</p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.zeldman.com/daily/1203i.shtml#semantic">The semantic web begins at home</a></p><p>The site for the First European Semantic Web Symposium is one of the least semantic websites ever produced.</p></td></tr></table>