<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Transitional//EN"
        "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-transitional.dtd">
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xml:lang="en" lang="en">
<head>
	<meta http-equiv="content-type" content="text/html; charset=utf-8" />
	<title>Referrers</title>
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="refer.css" type="text/css" />
	<meta name="robots" content="noindex" />
</head>
	<body>			
		<table align="center" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"><tr><td colspan="4" class="noliner"><a href="index.php">refresh</a> | glimpse: <a href="index.php?glimpse=1">24hr</a>  <a href="index.php?glimpse=2">48hr</a>  <a href="index.php?glimpse=3">72hr</a>  <a href="index.php?glimpse=7">1week</a>   | <a href="?queries=1">queries</a> | <a href="?format=help">help</a></td></tr><tr><td width="500"><p>RSS feed for <a href="http://coinz.org">co][nz.org</a></p><hr /><p><a href="http://coinz.org/archives/?date=20040103&id=107359996356905776">Acid trip</a></p><p>An interesting series of drawings performed by an artist under the influence of LSD as part of a study funded by the US government back in the 50's. "I can feel my knees now". Can you?</p><hr /><p><a href="http://coinz.org/archives/?date=20040103&id=107314771579267272">Web design practices</a></p><p>Heidi Adkisson's University of Washington masters thesis has resulted in Web Design Practices, a web site chock full of web design-related user research. "Web Design Practices is a site devoted to helping designers understand what design practices are cur</p><hr /><p><a href="http://coinz.org/archives/?date=20031211&id=107117064733852237">A little one</a></p><p>Some friends just welcomed a little one into their lives this past Saturday. Congratulations John and Janna!</p><hr /><p><a href="http://coinz.org/archives/?date=20031016&id=106631801321074354">Mozilla.org redesign and internet suite updates</a></p><p>Mozilla.org is in the process of redesigning using web standards. It's tableless, CSS-driven layout almost even validates. Looking good! While you're there, grab the new versions of Mozilla, Firebird and Thunderbird.</p><hr /><p><a href="http://coinz.org/archives/?date=20031001&id=106614386550835132">Badge design contest</a></p><p>Wear It With Pride is hosting an ongoing competition for those who want to design and submit badge designs. Being a big fan of design-related contests, I plan on cranking out a couple myself.</p><hr /><p><a href="http://coinz.org/archives/?date=20030929&id=106485946295154344">Layout-o-matic</a></p><p>Wait a week, and someone will have built it. The mantra of the web, in my opinion. At any rate, if your tired of wrangling with div tags and CSS to create an elegant, cross-browser box model design, check out Layout-o-matic. Think of it as the Scrubbing B</p><hr /><p><a href="http://coinz.org/archives/?date=20030919&id=106400337364759402">List-o-matic</a></p><p>Sick of hand-coding your XHTML list-based navigation menus? Time for List-o-matic, then. List-o-matic is a web-based wizard that helps you generate inline navigational lists using XHTML and CSS. Good, time saving stuff.</p><hr /><p><a href="http://coinz.org/archives/?date=20030919&id=106398603465470246">Developer and Power Users Tools</a></p><p>Scott Hanselman has an excellent list of developer and power users tools posted on one of his many blogs. "If it saves me time, and seamlessly integrates with my life, it's the bomb." Right on!</p><hr /><p><a href="http://coinz.org/archives/?date=20030917&id=106374480317892513">Attention web designers: A sticky for your monitor</a></p><p>You'd think by now that the saying "your website is for your customer, not for you" goes, well, without saying. Unfortunately for all of the end users out there, that just isn't the case. But it's not just the rookie designer or the design committees that</p><hr /><p><a href="http://coinz.org/archives/?date=20030916&id=106373862641143938">A month in the life</a></p><p>While I haven't done anything quite constructive as creating a recipe for Silly Putty, I have managed to purchase and move into a new home (hence the silence). Given the fact that I'm now if debt for the first time ever, I'm expecting to have more than en</p></td></tr></table>