<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Transitional//EN"
        "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-transitional.dtd">
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xml:lang="en" lang="en">
<head>
	<meta http-equiv="content-type" content="text/html; charset=utf-8" />
	<title>Referrers</title>
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="refer.css" type="text/css" />
	<meta name="robots" content="noindex" />
</head>
	<body>			
		<table align="center" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"><tr><td colspan="4" class="noliner"><a href="index.php">refresh</a> | glimpse: <a href="index.php?glimpse=1">24hr</a>  <a href="index.php?glimpse=2">48hr</a>  <a href="index.php?glimpse=3">72hr</a>  <a href="index.php?glimpse=7">1week</a>   | <a href="?queries=1">queries</a> | <a href="?format=help">help</a></td></tr><tr><td width="500"><p>RSS feed for <a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/">bradchoate.com</a></p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/001774.php">Happy new year and so forth</a></p><p><p>What&#8217;s happening? Well, Thanksgiving, Christmas and New Year&#8217;s day have all come and gone. Vacation and holiday days have been spent. A full week of work is in progress.</p><p>We&#8217;re just moments away from the <a href="http://stream.apple.akadns.net/">Macworld keynote</a>. Something that has new meaning to me this year.</p><p>I now have Virtual PC on my Mac. I can run just about anything on this baby. I can also develop for Linux, PC and Mac on this hardware. <em>Nice.</em></p><p>In Movable Type news, I&#8217;ve got some cool upgrades to a bunch of my plugins in the works. MT 3.0 should be in beta testing soon.</p><p>I&#8217;m planning a major rearchitecture of this site soon. Not really a redesign, but my URLs need fixing.</p><p>Last year was an <em>abysmal</em> year for my weblog. 86 entries? Just terrible. Hope to do a little better here on out.</p><p>Finally, a request I&#8217;ve been meaning to make. I&#8217;ve got a ton of free space on my iPod to fill and I need some suggestions. I&#8217;m probably the last person to discover Coldplay, so please enlighten me. (I&#8217;ll just say I&#8217;m not a big fan of country music, but folk is ok.)</p></p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/001765.php">'Bout Time</a></p><p><p><img height="290" src="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/images/rotk_tease.jpg" width="373"></p><p>I&#8217;ve not read one bad review yet.</p><p>Well, except maybe for <a href="http://msnbc.msn.com/id/3718931/">this sour puss</a> (although, less review, more rant or <em>something</em>).</p><p>Expectations are high to say the least. I hope Peter Jackson gets proper honors this year. He certainly deserves it.</p><p>Showtime is at 12:01 A.M., roughly 1 hour, 21 minutes from now&#8230;</p></p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/001733.php">Missing something</a></p><p><p>So a few days ago, for the first time in two weeks I fired up my former laptop, running Windows XP Pro. I had to clean it up, prepping it for sale since I don&#8217;t have much need for two laptops at the moment.</p><p>Within two minutes of logging in, I was greeted with something that I have been missing since switching to Mac OS X. Here it is:</p><p><img height="391" src="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/images/ugh_windows_update.gif" width="504"></p><p>Yep. Windows Update dutifully reported to me that there were no less than <strong>four</strong> critical updates all of which were to circumvent some attacker from gaining complete control over my computer. I guess it&#8217;s a good thing it&#8217;s been sitting very idle and off.</p><p>Don&#8217;t get me wrong &#8212; Mac OS X has a software update feature too. But by and large, it brings me new features and goodies. How refreshing. Every once and a while it includes a service update to some portion of the underlying system (like sendmail, which fortunately was replaced with postfix in Panther).</p></p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/001740.php">I don't know about you, but...</a></p><p><ul><li>I wish PgUp and PgDn on a Mac would move the cursor and not just the view. That would be nice.</li><li>I despise any DVD that has a pre-menu opening sequence that lasts more than 5 seconds. No, make that 3.</li><li>I won&#8217;t be doin&#8217; no <a href="http://sidetalkin.com/">sidetalkin&#8217;</a>.</li><li>It annoys me greatly that the Xbox requires the purchase of a <a href="http://xbox.com/en-US/hardware/dvdplaybackkit.htm">remote to operate</a> the on-board DVD player functions (in contrast to the PS2 which lets you use a controller). Just another reminder of why I don&#8217;t use Windows anymore.</li><li>I&#8217;m off work today (aka the &#8220;Zero Hour&#8221; for <em>Matrix: Revolutions</em>). IMAX, here I come.</li><li>I understand now why every Mac owner I&#8217;ve met is <a href="http://www.wired.com/news/mac/0,2125,0--60,00.html">fanatical about their Macintosh</a>.</li><li>I think my daughter makes a <a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/gallery/album40/DSCN0999">pretty cute dalmation</a>.</li><li>I&#8217;m starting to wonder if Movable Type Pro is ever coming out.</li><li>I&#8217;d like to take the Verizon &#8220;Can You Hear Me Now?&#8221; guy on a tour around where I live.</li><li>The <a href="http://pocket.ign.com/articles/457/457945p1.html">first look</a> at the Sony PSP looks nice (concept model).</li></ul></p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/001728.php">Happy Panther Day</a></p><p><p>I was pretty surprised to find that although Apple was not publicly offering a free OS X 10.3 upgrade to new PowerBook owners, they in fact were (and perhaps still are). I qualified for a free upgrade (well, free plus $19.95 for shipping and handling) according to their <a href="http://www.apple.com/macosx/uptodate/">Mac OS X Up-To-Date</a> web service. I even put in my purchase date as September 26th.</p><p>Well, it arrived today. And it&#8217;s installed. And it&#8217;s just spiffy. Unfortunately, it breaks some things. Specifically, several third-party things. Fortunately, those things are getting patched right now to work with Panther. <a href="http://rsug.itd.umich.edu/software/fugu/">Fugu</a> has been patched already. So has <a href="http://wwwbruegge.in.tum.de/projects/hydra/subethaedit/">SubEthaEdit</a>. I&#8217;m still waiting for <a href="http://sente.epfl.ch/software/GPGMail/">GPGMail</a>, <a href="http://www.unsanity.com/haxies/wsx/">WindowShade X</a> and <a href="http://culater.net/osd/PithHelmet/PithHelmet.html">PithHelmet</a>. Things that still work: <a href="http://www.obdev.at/products/launchbar/">LaunchBar</a>, <a href="http://www.sprote.com/clutter/">Clutter</a>, <a href="http://synergy.wincent.com/">Synergy</a>, <a href="http://www.barebones.com/products/bbedit/index.shtml">BBEdit</a>, <a href="http://fire.sourceforge.net/">Fire</a>, <a href="http://www.opendarwin.org/projects/osx2x/">osx2x</a>, <a href="http://www.bresink.de/osx/TinkerTool.html">TinkerTool</a>.</p><p><a href="http://www.macrabbit.com/cssedit/">CSSEdit</a> appears to be my CSS editor of choice at the moment. The latest release supports live previews. Unfortunately it doesn&#8217;t provide any feedback with regard to compatibility with the various browsers at the moment. But I think it has a good future.</p><p>Oh, and something else I am waiting on&#8212; the Panther-compatible <a href="http://cvsfinder.sourceforge.net/">cvsfinder</a>. Someone who reads my site is a developer on this project and was good enough to give me a heads-up on it. It strives to be the Mac version of TortoiseCVS and it looks like it&#8217;s off to a good start. Version 0.1 was released just the other day and during the brief moment that I was able to run it, it worked pretty well (read: didn&#8217;t cause a kernel panic).</p><p>I don&#8217;t have time to write a full review of it &#8212; especially considering I&#8217;ve just been using it for a little bit, but <a href="http://diveintomark.org/">Mark</a> has the jump on all of us, so <a href="http://diveintoosx.org/panther/">go read his</a>.</p></p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/001721.php">Happy Birthday, OOo</a></p><p><p><a href="http://www.openoffice.org/about_us/birthday3.html">Happy birthday</a>, Open Office. You&#8217;re three already!</p><p>And while I&#8217;m at it, please release 1.1 for Mac OS X!</p><p>That is all.</p></p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/001720.php">Warm Fuzzies</a></p><p><p>Mark Morford&#8217;s <a href="http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?file=/gate/archive/2003/10/01/notes100103.DTL">Lick Me, I&#8217;m a Macintosh</a> is a great account of the Apple out-of-box experience. It saves me the trouble of having to describe the experience, since mine matches his, word-for-word.</p><p>For those of you that look confused right now, I realize that I have been talking about switching to Linux and here I go and buy into the Mac? Well, perhaps I should have been more clear&#8212; I&#8217;m leaving Windows-land for Un*x territory. For PC hardware, that means running Linux. But I decided to buy a Mac because it&#8217;s the <a href="http://www.apple.com/macosx/features/unix/">best packaging of Unix</a> out there. FreeBSD at that. Looks, brains and brawn. That&#8217;s what I love about my PowerBook.</p><h4>Hardware</h4><p>Powerwise, I&#8217;m very pleased. <a href="http://www.cinebench.com/">CineBench 2003</a> shows it&#8217;s 1.25 GHz processor outpaces my former 2.4 GHz Pentium 4 laptop (non-mobile processor at that). It also runs cooler and unbelieveably quieter than any Intel laptop I&#8217;ve ever seen. And it&#8217;s 3 pounds lighter (at 5.6 pounds) and has a smaller footprint.</p><p>I&#8217;m still learning all the keyboard shortcuts. One thing that puzzles me about Apple is that they adore the simplicity of a single-button mouse (and trackpad which I&#8217;m stuck with), but in order to use the context popup menus, you have to hold down the Ctrl key <strong>and</strong> press the mouse button. Wouldn&#8217;t it be simpler to press a second mouse button instead? Seems more accessible and less confusing to me. I have a notebook mouse that I use and the 2nd mouse button works just fine, I&#8217;m just arguing that Apple should rethink just how user-friendly it is to make single-button mice these days.</p><p>I&#8217;m also a little annoyed that the keyboard on the 15&#8221; PowerBook is identical to the 12&#8221; one. It would have been nice to have a &#8220;Del&#8221; key that deletes the letter at the cursor instead of having to do Fn+Delete to do that. And can someone explain the extra &#8220;enter&#8221; key down by the arrow keys? That would been a good place for the &#8220;Del&#8221; key. Is anyone ever going to use that to press &#8220;enter&#8221;? Are there any good utilities out there for doing key-remapping?</p><h4>Software</h4><p>I&#8217;ve started gathering software, and so far I&#8217;ve registered <a href="http://ranchero.com/netnewswire/">NetNewsWire</a> &#8212; that was a no-brainer. I&#8217;ve also downloaded <a href="http://www.sprote.com/clutter/">Clutter</a> <del>but for some reason it&#8217;s not wanting to run</del> (Updated StuffIt to 8.0.1 and re-extracted Clutter, all better now). <a href="http://fire.sourceforge.net/">Fire</a> is a great multi-service IM client. I wish GPG-keyed messaging were more common place in other clients though. John Gruber pointed at <a href="http://www.obdev.at/products/launchbar/">LaunchBar</a> the other day and I&#8217;ll be registering that too. My OS X media for Photoshop should be here soon (Adobe has a process for switching from Windows to Mac or vice-versa. You just pay the shipping on the replacement media). <a href="http://www.barebones.com/products/bbedit/">BBEdit</a> looks like the best native editor, but it&#8217;s pricey (<a href="http://jedit.org/">jEdit</a> is a good editor, but it just doesn&#8217;t have that native Aqua look and feel). And hopefully OpenOffice 1.1 will be released soon for OS X. <a href="http://mozilla.org/products/firebird/">Firebird</a> is installed, but I find myself using Safari more because it&#8217;s just so fast. Suggestions for other must-have Mac software are welcome!</p><h4>iTMS</h4><p>I still haven&#8217;t found a good replacement for <a href="http://listen.com/">Listen Rhapsody</a>. I wish they would port their client to the Mac &#8212; given the success of the iTunes Music Store, maybe they are. While I&#8217;m at it, let me say that the iTunes Music Store is very nice and a good way to buy music, but I&#8217;m really annoyed by the fact that you can&#8217;t buy MP3s or convert purchased AAC files to MP3. Come on, Apple. You might as well make it an option. I can do it anyway by burning the AACs to CD and then re-importing back into iTunes anyhow. Given that, what is the point of the DRM stuff at all? Am I missing something? Oh yeah, the RIAA would flip if Apple sold uncontrollable MP3s.</p><p>Anyway, I&#8217;m having fun with both my new Linux and OS X systems. They play very nice together too. If you&#8217;re afraid to switch, don&#8217;t be. The water is fine.</p></p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/001709.php">Settling in with the penguin</a></p><p><p>My RedHat 9 workstation is doing great. It now has a 17&#8221; widescreen LCD panel attached to it. Plays DVDs using <a href="http://www.dtek.chalmers.se/groups/dvd/">Ogle</a> (which even does the DVD title menus), MPEG served by <a href="http://xine.sourceforge.net/">xine</a>. CD burning with <a href="http://www.xcdroast.org/">X-CD-Roast</a>.</p><p>Despite my <a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/linuxforwindows.php">reservations about the harmfulness of Wine</a>, it is useful. <a href="http://lindows.prodigydigital.com/tutorials/photoshop7.html">Photoshop 7 runs just fine</a> (thanks, Sean!). So does Trillian Pro. But if I&#8217;m really going native, shouldn&#8217;t I be using the <a href="http://www.gimp.org/">Gimp</a> and <a href="http://gaim.sourceforge.net/">GAIM</a> instead?</p><p>I created my first &#8220;Hello World&#8221; app using Glade and GNU C last night. Boy, it feels good to explore new territory.</p><p><a href="http://meld.sourceforge.net/">Meld</a> &#8212; my Linux replacement for <a href="http://winmerge.sourceforge.net/">WinMerge</a> (why&#8217;d they have to write that with Visual Studio?).</p><h4>Thinking Different</h4><p>As for portable computing, check out <a href="http://www.apple.com/powerbook/index15.html">my new ride.</a> Yes, really. <a href="http://www.kottke.org/03/09/030929thirty.html">Peer</a> <a href="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2003/09/26/NewMac">pressure</a> is a terrible thing. I <em>had</em> way too much money. Now Apple does. I think at this point in my technological life, anything but Windows will do.</p><p>By the way&#8212; considering Apple&#8217;s fondness for that <a href="http://www.wired.com/news/mac/0,2125,60597,00.html">brushed metal/chrome</a> look, you&#8217;d better grab one of these color Macs before they revert the platform back to grayscale.</p><p>I also now know that it takes a <em>long</em> time for Airborne Express to deliver from Shanghai.</p><p>Relevant: <a href="http://www.macdevcenter.com/pub/a/mac/2003/09/30/dock.html">What&#8217;s on Your Dock?</a></p><p>And good news&#8212; the Gyration mouse and keyboard <a href="http://www.gyration.com/ultra_faq.htm#5">are OS X compatible</a> (I just wish <a href="http://synergy2.sourceforge.net/">Synergy</a> was too).</p><h4>With Anticipation</h4><p><a href="http://lordoftherings.net/">Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King trailer</a> now available.</p><p><a href="http://whatisthematrix.warnerbros.com/">Matrix Revolutions theater trailer</a> now available.</p><h4>Software Upgrades</h4><p><a href="http://www.openoffice.org/">Open Office 1.1</a>. If this thing doesn&#8217;t satisfy your &#8220;Officeware&#8221; needs, then maybe you&#8217;ve seen too many MS Office training videos.</p><p><a href="http://use.perl.org/articles/03/09/26/2231256.shtml?tid=6">Perl 5.8.1</a> is out.</p><p>A Mozilla <a href="http://mozillazine.org/talkback.html?article=3753">Firebird 0.7 release candidate</a> is available. Working great on Win32 and Linux.</p><p>Relevant: <a href="http://www.deftone.com/blogzilla/archives/another_alternative_firebird_and_thunderbird_icon.html">Beautiful icons</a> for Mozilla Firebird and Thunderbird.</p><p>MusicMatch 8.1 (or is it 8.10?) is out and now has a <a href="http://www.musicmatch.com/download/music_intro.htm?os=pc&amp;mode=%20input&amp;BTD=1&amp;DID=">music store</a> (99 cents/track too).</p><p>I noticed that my ThinkDB Palm applet got acquired by DataViz and has morphed into <a href="http://www.dataviz.com/products/smartlisttogo/index.html">SmartLists To Go</a>. They were nice enough to give me a free upgrade to the latest release, free of charge.</p><p>And another week has gone by and <a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/001653.php">MT-Textile 2</a> is <em>still</em> in beta. When is that guy going to release already?</p><h4>Miscellany</h4><p><a href="http://popcorn.kalsey.com/">Scout Popcorn</a>. You know you want it. (Powered by <a href="http://www.oscommerce.com/">osCommerce</a>, a free PHP e-Commerce engine.)</p><p><a href="http://www.e4engineering.com/item.asp?id=50014&amp;type=news">Ultra High Def Video</a>. Glad I haven&#8217;t invested in HDTV yet&#8230; try 4 times the resolution. But at a price&#8212; 3.5 terabytes for a measly 18 minutes of video. So where do you buy a 500 terabyte TiVo? I don&#8217;t think they have the processors yet to compress streams that big.</p><p>The source code to <a href="http://dynamic2.gamespy.com/~homeworld/site/modules.php?op=modload&amp;name=News&amp;file=article&amp;sid=66">Homeworld 1</a> was released.</p><p>Voting is <a href="http://www.intertwingly.net/wiki/pie/NameFinalVote">over</a>, so it must be Atom.</p><p>David Dvorkin: <a href="http://www.dvorkin.com/essays/unemben.htm">The Surprising Benefits of Being Unemployed</a> (of note: the sidebar on <em>Smallville</em> under &#8220;Power Shower&#8221;).</p><p>I finally got around to putting another 60 GB drive in my TiVo. Now we can record twice the number of cartoons for Savannah. Greeeat. <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0596005539/">TiVo Hacks</a> was somewhat helpful, but I&#8217;d like the book a lot more if it were more relevant for the Series 2.</p><p>Wow&#8230; that was quite cathartic.</p></p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/001705.php">Switching to Shrike</a></p><p><p>RedHat Linux 9 (codename <a href="http://www.redhat.com/software/linux/">Shrike</a>) makes for a nice OS. I have it installed on my home desktop PC. Which sits beside my G3 which are connected to a <a href="http://linksys.com/Products/product.asp?grid=33&amp;scid=35&amp;prid=508">Linksys router</a> (<a href="http://linksys.com/support/gpl.asp">running Linux</a>). These are in the same living room as our TV which has a TiVo &#8212; another Linux device. I don&#8217;t know if any of this is worrisome to Microsoft, but it should be.</p><p>The only Windows machine I have left is my laptop. It still runs XP. I&#8216;d switch it right now if there was a driver available for my 54g WiFi PC card. Linksys has no ETA for it, but I don&#8217;t think there are <strong>any</strong> 54g cards available for Linux yet (<a href="http://www.linux-wlan.com/linux-wlan/index.html#Compatibility">check for yourself</a>).</p><p>While I find RedHat 9 to be a decent desktop OS for me, it&#8217;s certainly not for everyone. Yes, installation was a breeze, but general maintenance is not for the timid. For example: enabling anti-aliased fonts in XFree86. Or installing the latest nVidia drivers (this one required the kernel source code to install for my machine). Or adding the NTFS support so you can mount and copy files from a NTFS-formatted volume. Here&#8217;s hoping that RedHat continues to improve usability. It would be nice to see it reach the level of ease seen in Mac OS X.</p><p>Speaking of Apple and Macs, I&#8217;m still tempted to buy an Apple G5. This weekend we took a trip to the Apple store near us so I could drool up-close-and-personal-like with the latest goods. Man, that place is built to frisk you of $1000-$6000 depending on what you can bear to part with. I would love to have a dual-processor G5 in my home, but I&#8217;m afraid I would be spending most of my time staring at a terminal window. Something I can just as easily do with a $200 PC. But wouldn&#8217;t that terminal window look <strong><em>spectacular</em></strong> on an Apple Cinema display? I somehow managed to walk out of the Apple store barehanded, but I don&#8217;t know how much longer I can hold out.</p><p>Speaking of freakin&#8217; huge monitors, the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/B000069LHV/002-2171592-6530456">Samsung SyncMaster 240T</a> is quite a beauty. It has the Apple Cinema 23&#8221; beat in many ways: one more inch of real estate. It has digital and analog inputs &#8212; even S-video. You can split the screen between multiple sources &#8212; great for watching a movie while you&#8217;re working or reading. I&#8217;m afraid I might have to buy a more powerful video card to support a DVI-powered 1920&times;1200 display.</p><p>But I digress.</p><p>Software-wise, I feel pretty comfortable. OpenOffice is installed and running nicely. Mozilla Firebird runs better than ever on Linux. I can share files with my Mac thanks to the <a href="http://www.samba.org/">Samba</a> support both have. <a href="http://www.jedit.org/">jEdit</a> is identical to the Windows version. No need for Putty since ssh is installed (and patched) right out of the &#8220;box&#8221;. <a href="http://gaim.sourceforge.net/">Gaim</a> is no Trillian, but will do for now. The <a href="http://www.gimp.org/">Gimp</a> interface will take some getting used to (Won&#8217;t someone add a Photoshop-like interface option for it? Photoshop-compatible keyboard mappings would be nice.) I still can&#8217;t find a good replacement for <a href="http://bradsoft.com/topstyle/">TopStyle Pro</a>. So Nick&#8230; if you&#8217;re listening&#8212; any plans for a Linux version? You have heard of Kylix, right?</p></p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/001704.php">Acer's New "Jekyll/Hyde" Laptop</a></p><p><p>Check this out: <a href="http://www.pcworld.com/news/article/0,aid,112577,00.asp">PCWorld.com - Acer Readies New Notebook, Tablet PC</a></p><p>I think this is a first &#8212; a laptop that is shipping with <strong>both</strong> Windows and Linux. OK, it doesn&#8217;t have a full copy of Linux in there, but it uses Linux to power the &#8220;instant-on&#8221; mode that is used to playback DVD and CD media. Push a button and 10 seconds later this thing is ready to show a movie on it&#8217;s 15.4 inch display. Not bad. Is this the first computer to ship from the factory in a dual-boot-ish configuration?</p><p>See also:</p><ul><li><a href="http://global.acer.com/about/news.asp?id=6344">Acer press release</a> (which doesn&#8217;t even mention Linux)</li><li><a href="http://www.gizmodo.com/archives/008958.php#008958">Gizmodo Archives</a> </li></ul></p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/001691.php">Clearing the dust</a></p><p><p>Someone should develop a CSS/PHP or CSS/Javascript technique that makes your site look like it&#8217;s collecting dust the longer it goes without an update. By now, this site would be completely covered. A whole month since my last post. I can do better.</p><p>Anyway, to catch up. Lots of things have been going on, mostly family related. Savannah had her third birthday. She starts preschool this coming Monday. She&#8217;s quite excited about it of course. Seth had his first birthday &#8212; actually, he&#8217;s having it today!</p><p>And let&#8217;s not forget that Georgia is expecting again. She&#8217;s about 2 months along. The due date is April 11th. Because of this, we&#8217;ve been looking at the real estate market to see if we can find a nice four bedroom that will contain us for the next 20 years or so.</p><p>Work has been going pretty well. We&#8217;re transitioning from Oracle to DB2, so that&#8217;s been interesting. We&#8217;ve also switched to Lotus Notes Release 6 &#8212; which is perhaps a safer platform than Outlook, but is missing an integrated <a href="http://spambayes.sourceforge.net/">Spambayes</a> and I really, really need a good spam solution for work (I would promise never again to post my e-mail address to a newsgroup, but it&#8217;s a little late now).</p><p>Other than that, I&#8217;ll share that I&#8217;m considering switching to <a href="http://www.interland.com/">Interland</a> for my hosting. They&#8217;re currently offering a $79/month server with specs similar or better to the server I&#8217;m using now. $240 a year is not pocket change to a family of 5. Also doesn&#8217;t hurt that they were in the <a href="http://news.netcraft.com/archives/2003/09/01/most_reliable_and_fastest_hosting_company_sites_during_august.html">top 10 most reliable hosts for August</a>.</p><p>I also checked all my plugin work into a CVS server hosted on this web server.  I&#8217;ll be using it as my development repository going forward. The CVS interface itself is not publicly accessible, but there is a web-based <a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/cvs">front end</a> if you care to peek around. You&#8217;ll find a few works in progress that are unreleased. Feedback is welcome. And please use the <a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/mantis">bug tracker</a> if you find something that needs fixing.</p><p>One more thing for closure &#8212; my friend Ron who was looking for a job has taken a teaching position for this school year, with medical benefits. I appreciate all the help with the &#8220;Hire Ron&#8221; campaign, but since he got the position on his own, so there is no prize (sorry Ron, but contest rules made you ineligible!).</p></p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/001672.php">Reasons for sticking with Windows</a></p><p><p>A diminishing list, but a list nonetheless:</p><ol><li><a href="http://bradsoft.com/topstyle/">TopStyle Pro</a></li><li><a href="http://www.adobe.com/photoshop">Adobe Photoshop</a> (Win/Mac only)</li><li><a href="http://www.trillian.cc/">Trillian Pro</a></li><li><a href="http://www.tortoisecvs.org/">TortoiseCVS</a></li><li><a href="http://listen.com/">Listen.com</a> Rhapsody</li></ol><p>And&#8230; I think that&#8217;s it. No, no games. The great ones are cross platform. And most other good Windows games are at least available on the Xbox. And note the absence of Microsoft Office and Microsoft DevStudio. Everything else I use today is available on other platforms: Mozilla for browsing, jEdit or XEmacs for editing code, ssh and VNC for remote access, OpenOffice for officeware, Perl and Java for development. I could easily switch to the Mac, but then I&#8217;d be losing Trillian. Now that would be a <em>real</em> sacrifice. iChat? Please, no <a href="http://www.apple.com/macosx/jaguar/ichat.html">bubbles</a>, thank you.</p><p>Also note that of the list above, TortoiseCVS is the only open source application. </p><p>As for Linux, there have been significant strides in making the whole user experience better, but I&#8217;m just not sold yet. For a server, I wouldn&#8217;t use anything else, but not for my workstation.</p><p>One thing that may have to happen before I switch to Linux for my workstation/laptop: demoting X off the Linux desktop. I don&#8217;t think X will ever go away (nor should it), but it shouldn&#8217;t power the desktop for Linux. It&#8217;s just not able to compete with the overhead that the X-protocol adds to things. A wise thing to do is to do what Apple did: create a solid desktop shell and provide X support for legacy apps. There&#8217;s a big opportunity here. Linux is winning the war on the embedded and server-side fronts. A solid desktop would make all difference for the rest of us.</p><p>Oh, did I mention that the <a href="http://www.trillian.cc/sneakpeek/">Trillian 2.0 beta</a> is available for us &#8220;Pro&#8221; users?</p></p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/001667.php">Sitewide RSS</a></p><p><p>Well, it looks like this weblog is becoming just a Movable Type how-to blog. Well, in keeping with that theme, here&#8217;s a little &#8220;part two&#8221; companion piece for <a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/001656.php">Doing your whole site with MT</a> (one of my worst blog titles, ever).</p><p>Now that you&#8217;ve got your whole site MT-powered, what about your RSS feed? Chances are you, have one for your weblog, but what about one for everything? I&#8217;ve created one for my site, called <a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/sitewide.rss">sitewide.rss</a>. It lets folks keep track of every update that happens to my site, whether it be part of my weblog or not.</p><p>To get it to work, you have to do a little bit of work. It&#8217;s not much though, and once you&#8217;ve done it, it&#8217;s easy to maintain.</p><p>Without further warning, here&#8217;s the RSS template to do a sitewide RSS feed:</p>&lt;MTSimpleTemplate&gt;# customize the following line by setting the value to the # blog IDs that you want to include in your RSS feed:% SetVar name=&quot;blogs&quot; value=&quot;1,2,3,4,5&quot;&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;${PublishCharset}&quot;?&gt;&lt;rss version=&quot;2.0&quot;&gt;&lt;channel&gt;&lt;title&gt;My Web Site RSS Feed&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link&gt;http://www.example.com/&lt;/link&gt;&lt;description&gt;Site-wide feed for My Web Site&lt;/description&gt;&lt;language&gt;en-us&lt;/language&gt;&lt;managingEditor&gt;someone@example.com&lt;/managingEditor&gt;&lt;copyright&gt;Copyright ${Date format=&quot;%Y&quot;}&lt;/copyright&gt;&lt;lastBuildDate&gt;% GlobalEntries include_blogs=&quot;${GetVar name='blogs'}&quot; \%     lastn_modified=&quot;1&quot; sort_by=&quot;modified_on&quot; \%     sort_order=&quot;descend&quot; {${LastModified language=&quot;en&quot; format=&quot;%a, %d %b %Y %H:%M:%S&quot;} ${BlogTimezone no_colon=&quot;1&quot;}% } GlobalEntries&lt;/lastBuildDate&gt;&lt;pubDate&gt;${Date language=&quot;en&quot; format=&quot;%a, %d %b %Y %H:%M:%S&quot;}    ${BlogTimezone no_colon=&quot;1&quot;}&lt;/pubDate&gt;&lt;generator&gt;http://www.movabletype.org/?v=% Version&lt;/generator&gt;&lt;webMaster&gt;brad@bradchoate.com&lt;/webMaster&gt;&lt;ttl&gt;60&lt;/ttl&gt;% GlobalEntries include_blogs=&quot;${GetVar name='blogs'}&quot; \%     lastn_modified=&quot;15&quot; sort_by=&quot;modified_on&quot; \%     sort_order=&quot;descend&quot; {&lt;item&gt;&lt;title&gt;${EntryTitle remove_html=&quot;1&quot; encode_xml=&quot;1&quot;}&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link&gt;${EntryLink encode_xml=&quot;1&quot;}&lt;/link&gt;&lt;description&gt;${EntryBody encode_xml=&quot;1&quot;}${EntryMore encode_xml=&quot;1&quot;}&lt;/description&gt;&lt;guid isPermaLink=&quot;true&quot;&gt;${EntryPermalink}&lt;/guid&gt;&lt;category&gt;${BlogName encode_xml=&quot;1&quot;}: ${EntryCategory encode_xml=&quot;1&quot;}&lt;/category&gt;&lt;author&gt;${EntryAuthorEmail} (${EntryAuthor})&lt;/author&gt;&lt;pubDate&gt;${LastModified language=&quot;en&quot; format=&quot;%a, %d %b %Y %H:%M:%S&quot;}    ${BlogTimezone no_colon=&quot;1&quot;}&lt;/pubDate&gt;&lt;/item&gt;% } GlobalEntries&lt;/channel&gt;&lt;/rss&gt;&lt;/MTSimpleTemplate&gt;<p>Now, you&#8217;ll need to customize the above template by setting the &#8220;include_blogs&#8221; attribute of the &lt;MTGlobalEntries&gt; tag to list the weblog ID&#8217;s you wish to include in your RSS feed (this is listed in two places). You will also want to update the &lt;title&gt;, &lt;link&gt;, &lt;description&gt;, possibly &lt;language&gt;, and &lt;managingEditor&gt; elements. The above produces a &#8220;full&#8221; RSS feed. If you prefer to use excerpts, change the item-level &lt;description&gt; element to contain just: ${EntryExcerpt encode_xml=&quot;1&quot;}</p><h4>Installation</h4><p>For each weblog you want to index in your sitewide RSS feed, create a new index template in that weblog. Give it a title of &#8220;Sitewide RSS&#8221; and put the above template code in there. The output filename can be anything. I named my &#8220;sitewide.rss&#8221;. It should be marked to rebuild automatically.</p><p><em>Optional:</em> You may want to enter a filename in the &#8220;Link this template to a file&#8221; field. This will help make updates to any cross-blog templates easier since you want to make this template identical across all the weblogs indexed. For example, you might choose &#8220;sitewide.tmpl&#8221; as the filename. By specifying the same filename for your &#8220;Sitewide RSS&#8221; template in each weblog, they will all be kept in synch.</p><p><em>Optional:</em> If you use template modules to define <a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/mtmacros.php">macros</a> and things like that, you can link <em>those</em> templates to files and include them using the <a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/mtincludeex.php">IncludeEx plugin</a> which will process the MT tags within the file (as opposed to the &lt;MTInclude&gt; tag which doesn&#8217;t parse MT tags in files).</p><h4>Requirements</h4><p>Now to get this thing working, you&#8217;ll need a few plugins (you knew that was coming):</p><ul><li><a href="http://mt-plugins.org/archives/entry/globallistings.php">Global Listings</a> &#8212; an excellent cross-blog entry listing solution by Stepan Riha. You could use my <a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/mtsql.php">SQL</a> plugin instead, but I chose this one since it works for any MT installation, not just those running on a SQL database.</li><li><a href="http://mt-plugins.org/archives/entry/lastmodified.php">Last Modified</a> &#8212; by Kevin Shay. Lets you grab the last modification date for your MT entries. The sitewide feed should be in order by last modified date since your entries will include pages that get regular updates. Listing by last modification will reveal those changes to your subscribers.</li><li><a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/mtsimpletemplate.php">Simple Template</a> &#8212; well, not technically required, but the example above is uses it and I&#8217;m trying to get everyone else to use it too because I love it so.</li></ul><p>If you&#8217;ve done it right, any new entries or updates made to any weblog that has this template will update your sitewide RSS feed. </p></p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/mozilla.php">Mozilla</a></p><p><p>Welcome to my <a href="http://www.mozilla.org/">Mozilla</a> resource page.</p><p>Adam Kalsey reminded me of Venkman today and I realized it wasn&#8217;t on my big Mozilla list, so for those of you that haven&#8217;t used it and are still debugging your JavaScript with alert() calls, go get:</p><ul><li><ins><a href="http://www.hacksrus.com/~ginda/venkman/">Venkman Debugger</a>: Will literally save your life (or at least many, many hours of it).</ins></li></ul><p>The following is a growing list (newest items will be added at the top) of resources for the Mozilla browser and related projects.</p><ul><li><ins><a href="http://checky.mozdev.org/">Checky</a>: <strong>The</strong> Mozilla add-on for insuring your web pages validate and are standards-compliant.</ins></li><li><ins><a href="http://devedge.netscape.com/toolbox/sidebars/">DevEdge Sidebar</a>: provides a bunch of standards documentation at your fingertips covering subjects like HTML, CSS, DOM, JavaScript, etc. (via <a href="http://www.meyerweb.com/eric/thoughts/2003b.html#t20030502">meyerweb</a>)</ins></li><li><ins><a href="http://placenamehere.com/pnhtoolbar/">PNH Developer Toolbar</a>: A bunch of handy web tools all grouped into one package (links to W3C documentation, page test tools, page layout tools and more).</ins></li><li><a href="http://gemal.dk/mozilla/mozdev.html">Mozilla in testing and debugging web sites</a>: How to use the power of Mozilla to make web development easier.</li><li><a href="http://a.wholelottanothing.org/features.blah/entry/006650">Mozilla: Blogging&#8217;s Killer App</a>: Matt&#8217;s excellent take on Mozilla from a blogger&#8217;s perspective.</li><li><a href="http://home.snafu.de/tilman/mozilla/">The Mozilla Museum</a>: Mozilla nostalgia at it&#8217;s finest.</li><li><a href="http://www.xulplanet.com/ndeakin/arts/reasons.html">101 things that Mozilla can do that IE cannot</a>: Why you should be using Mozilla instead of IE.</li><li><a href="http://www.oreillynet.com/mozilla/">O&#8217;Reilly Network&#8217;s Mozilla DevCenter</a>: Lots of technical goodies in here.</li><li><a href="http://www.geocities.com/pratiksolanki/">Hidden Mozilla Preferences</a>: Lots of stuff you weren&#8217;t meant to see or perhaps things they just didn&#8217;t bother creating a UI widget for.</li><li><a href="http://www.deftone.com/blogzilla/">Blogzilla</a>: It&#8217;s a blog about Mozilla, get it?</li><li><a href="http://www.xulplanet.com/">XULPlanet</a>: Mozilla app development hub.</li><li><a href="http://www.mozdev.org/">mozdev.org</a>: Tons of add-ons, themes and other resources for Mozilla.</li><li><a href="http://www.mozillazine.org/">MozillaZine</a>: Your source for Mozilla news and advocacy. (<a href="http://www.mozillazine.org/weblogs/">Weblogs are here</a>)</li><li><a href="http://www.mozilla.org/">Mozilla.org</a>: The starting place for Mozilla.</li></ul><p>As a &#8216;living&#8217; blog entry, it will get bumped (timestamp updated) as new resources are listed. &#8216;ins&#8217; tags will be used to indicate new content.</p></p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/mtsimpletemplate.php">Simple Template</a></p><p><p>Movable Type templates aren&#8217;t too difficult to write, but they can be difficult to read. So I&#8217;ve whipped up another plugin to fix that. Simple Template is a plugin that provides an alternative syntax for Movable Type templates<sup><a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/mtsimpletemplate.php#fn1">1</a></sup>.</p><h4>Availability</h4><p>You can download this plugin here: <a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/downloads/mtsimpletemplate-1_21.zip">mtsimpletemplate-1_21.zip</a></p><h4>Installation</h4><p>To install, place the &#8216;simpletemplate.pl&#8217; file in your Movable Type &#8220;plugins&#8221; directory. The &#8216;simpletemplate.pm&#8217; file should be placed in a &#8216;bradchoate&#8217; subdirectory underneath your Movable Type &#8220;extlib&#8221; directory. Your installation should look like this:</p><ul><li>(mt home)/plugins/simpletemplate.pl</li><li>(mt home)/extlib/bradchoate/simpletemplate.pm</li></ul><p>Refer to the Movable Type documentation for more information regarding plugins.</p><h4>Description</h4><p>This plugin provides an alternative format for your Movable Type templates.</p><p>Tags made available through this plugin:</p><ul><li>&lt;MTSimpleTemplate&gt; - The container tag that translates the &#8220;simple&#8221; template format into a regular Movable Type template.</li><li>&lt;MTEval&gt; - Container tag that allows you to use embedded expressions for any Movable Type tag.</li><li>&lt;MTSetVarBlock&gt; - Similar to the SetVar tag, but is a container tag where the value is placed within the tag.</li></ul><h4>&lt;MTSimpleTemplate&gt;</h4><p>The SimpleTemplate tag should be placed around your entire template so it can process it for the &#8220;simple&#8221; template syntax it offers.</p><p>These attributes are allowed:</p><ul><li><strong>pragma</strong>An optional parameter that allows you to define the character(s) used to indicate the Movable Type tag data. The default is &#8216;%&#8217;.</li><li><strong>comment</strong>An optional parameter that allows you to define the character(s) used to indicate comments within the template. The default is &#8216;#&#8217;.</li><li><strong>no_build</strong>If specified, the output from this tag will be the Movable Type template code it produces. Normally, the output is the compiled result of the template.</li></ul><h5>Usage</h5><p>Here&#8217;s a very simple Movable Type template:</p>&lt;$MTEntryBody$&gt;&lt;MTIfEntryExtended&gt;Extended text: &lt;$MTEntryMore$&gt;&lt;/MTIfEntryExtended&gt;<p>Here is the same thing in &#8220;simple&#8221; format:</p>&lt;MTSimpleTemplate&gt;% EntryBody% EntryIfExtended:Extended text: ${EntryMore}% :EntryIfExtended&lt;/MTSimpleTemplate&gt;<p>Note that there are two forms you can use to produce MT tags:</p><ol><li>Pragma format: a line starting with the &#8216;%&#8217; character (or you can customize this using the &#8216;pragma&#8217; attribute of the SimpleTemplate tag) is seen as a Movable Type instruction. Exactly one MT tag may be produced per pragma. If the pragma line ends with &#8220;:&#8221; (or &#8220;{&#8221;, &#8220;(&#8221;, &#8220;[&#8221;) it is considered an open MT tag. If the pragma starts with &#8220;:&#8221; (or &#8220;}&#8221;, &#8220;)&#8221;, &#8220;]&#8221;) it is considered a closing tag.</li><li>Inline format: ${Variable attribute=&quot;value&quot;}This is a simple way to express: &lt;$MTVariable attribute=&quot;value&quot;$&gt;</li></ol><p>Any Movable Type tags can be used with this &#8212; you would just refer to them without the usual &#8220;MT&#8221; prefix.</p><p>Here&#8217;s some more examples:</p>% Comments:&lt;div class=&quot;comments-body&quot;&gt;% CommentBody&lt;span class=&quot;comments-post&quot;&gt;Posted by: ${CommentAuthorLink spam_protect=&quot;1&quot;}at ${CommentDate}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;% :Comments<p>This demonstrates line-continuation with Simple Templates. If the pragma ends with &#8220;&#92;&#8221; and the next line is a pragma line, then it gets concatenated together:</p>% EntryDate \%   format=&quot;%Y-%m-%dT%H:%M:%S&quot;<p>becomes:</p>&lt;$MTEntryDate format=&quot;%Y-%m-%dT%H:%M:%S&quot;$&gt;<p>Container tags should be written like this:</p>% EntryIfExtended:Something something...% :EntryIfExtended<p>or this:</p>% EntryIfExtended {Something something...% } EntryIfExtended<p>or this:</p>% EntryIfExtended {Something something...% }<p>Non-container tags (like &lt;$MTEntryBody$&gt;) can be written like this:</p>% EntryBody<p>or this:</p>${EntryBody}<p>Comments may be included (default comment character is &#8216;#&#8217;) but the comment character must be at the start of the line (no spaces prior to it):</p># This is a comment.<h4>&lt;MTEval&gt;</h4><p>Evaluates embedded expressions within any arbitrary MT tag.</p><p>Attributes:</p><ul><li><strong>_tag</strong>If specified, the Eval tag functions as a proxy for the tag identified.  If unspecified, the Eval tag expects a single Movable Type tag to be enclosed within the Eval tag.</li></ul><p>For global filters, you can pass attribute names like this:</p>&lt;MTEval _tag=&quot;GetVar&quot; name=&quot;something&quot; 001lower_case=&quot;1&quot; 002upper_case=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;<p>This will cause the filters to be applied in the order they are numbered.You can even duplicate the global filter attribute name/value pairs,combining the operations in any order you wish.</p><h5>Usage:</h5>&lt;MTSetVar name=&quot;lastn&quot; value=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;MTEval _tag=&quot;Entries&quot; lastn=&quot;[MTGetVar name='lastn']&quot;&gt;  (Entry tags go here)&lt;/MTEval&gt;<p>Or:</p>&lt;MTSetVar name=&quot;lastn&quot; value=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;MTEval&gt;&lt;MTEntries lastn=&quot;[MTGetVar name='lastn']&quot;&gt;  (Entry tags go here)&lt;/MTEntries&gt;&lt;/MTEval&gt;<p>You can also use it for simple MT tags (non-container tags):</p>&lt;MTSetVar name=&quot;lastn&quot; value=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;MTSetVar name=&quot;variable&quot; value=&quot;lastn&quot;&gt;&lt;MTEval _tag=&quot;GetVar&quot; name=&quot;[MTGetVar name='variable']&quot; /&gt;<h4>&lt;MTSetVarBlock&gt;</h4><p>Allows you to define a complex string (multi-line, with tags and even Movable Type tags) for a variable.</p><ul><li><strong>name</strong>Name of variable to assign.</li></ul><h5>Usage:</h5>&lt;MTSetVarBlock name=&quot;my_info&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a very long block of text thatI'm using to describe myself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And so forth&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/MTSetVarBlock&gt;<h4>License</h4><p>Released under the <a href="http://www.opensource.org/licenses/mit-license.php">MIT license</a>.</p><h4>Changelog</h4><ul><li><strong>1.21</strong>: Bugfix to wrapper &lt;MTEval&gt; support.</li><li><strong>1.2</strong>: Added support for specifying multiple global filter attribute name/value pairs. They are also processed in the order specified.Made the = sign following the attribute names optional.Renamed the &#8220;no_compile&#8221; attribute to &#8220;no_build&#8221; (more accurate interminology).</li><li><strong>1.1</strong>: Added Eval and SetVarBlock tags. Implemented dynamic replacement of ${&#8230;} expressions within MT attributes.Defined default attribute names for many tags that only have a single attribute or have 1 required attribute that drives their function.</li><li><strong>1.0</strong>: Initial release.</li></ul><p><sup>1</sup> Personally, I like it &#8212; but the &#8220;simpler&#8221; aspect of this is my opinion of course, not necessarily yours.</p></p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/001656.php">Doing your whole site with MT</a></p><p><p><cite>Matt Haughey</cite> has a <a href="http://a.wholelottanothing.org/features.blah/entry/007162">great article</a> on how he uses Movable Type to do it all (apparently, Kottke <a href="http://www.kottke.org/03/07/030714new_sidebar_.html">does too&#8230;</a> can&#8217;t wait to see <em>his</em> article).</p><p>Anyhow, I wanted to share a tidbit in that vein. I&#8217;ve just set this up recently, and I&#8217;m in the process of moving the rest of my static content to use it.  What I did:</p><ol><li> Created a new Movable Type blog and named it &#8220;bradchoate.com: Static Content&#8221;.</li><li> Deleted all the Index templates.</li><li> Deleted all the archive templates, except for the Individual archive template.</li><li> Made sure individual archives were enabled.</li><li> Made the archive path the root directory of my web site.</li><li> Created categories for each directory I want to create content for (category name = directory name)</li><li> Used the following for the Individual Entry Archive filename template (specified on the &#8220;Archiving&#8221; page of your weblog configuration). Produces: &#8220;category/entry_title.html&#8221;:&lt;$MTEntryCategory    lower_case=&quot;1&quot;$&gt;&lt;MTIfNotEmpty    var=&quot;EntryCategory&quot;&gt;/&lt;/MTIfNotEmpty&gt;&lt;$MTEntryTitle    dirify=&quot;1&quot;$&gt;.html</li></ol><p>So with this setup, instead of using your Index templates for your separate pages, they all become their own entry. This seems more appropriate to me. It also lets you use the excerpt and keywords field to store additional metadata about that particular page. So when you build, the individual file created for my &#8220;About&#8221; entry is named &#8220;about/index.php&#8221; since it has a category of &#8220;About&#8221; and an entry title &#8220;Index&#8221;.</p><p>You can do your individual file archive template any number of ways. The technique above will rely on the category assignment to define what directory to put the file. Here are some alternatives:</p><ol><li> Category defines directory (ie: &#8220;About/Something&#8221;), entry title is the full filename including extension (ie: &#8220;summer_vacation.html&#8221;): Produces: &#8220;about/something/summer_vacation.html&#8221;:&lt;$MTEntryCategory    lower_case=&quot;1&quot;$&gt;&lt;MTIfNotEmpty    var=&quot;EntryCategory&quot;&gt;/&lt;/MTIfNotEmpty&gt;&lt;$MTEntryTitle$&gt;</li><li> Entry title is the full path and filename (ie: &#8220;about/something/summer_vacation.php&#8221;). Category isn&#8217;t used to name the file at all. Produces: &#8220;about/something/summer_vacation.php&#8221;:&lt;$MTEntryTitle$&gt;</li><li> Category defines directory path (category label looks like &#8220;about/something/&#8221;). Entry title is descriptive (ie: &#8220;Summer Vacation&#8221;). Produces &#8220;about/something/summer_vacation.html&#8221;:&lt;$MTEntryCategory$&gt;&lt;$MTEntryTitle    dirify=&quot;1&quot;$&gt;.html</li></ol><p>The &#8220;IfNotEmpty&#8221; tag (provided through the <a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/mtifempty.php">IfEmpty</a> plugin) allows you to test for no category assignment. If a category is not defined, then the &#8216;/&#8217; prefix is left off the filename, so the file would go into the top directory of the weblog.</p><p>This benefits of all this are many. Because now I can use <a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/mttextile.php">Textile formatting</a> for any page of my web site.  I can also make use of Movable Type&#8217;s search feature to search any page of my site instead of just my weblog content. I can also enable comments, trackback or whatever for any page I&#8217;d like.</p></p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/001653.php">Thither MT-Textile 2 (beta)</a></p><p><p>Ok, so Dean has <a href="http://www.textism.com/article/739/">taken the wraps</a> off his version, so I shall do the same.  MT-Textile 2 is back in beta. I assure you, there are bugs to be found, so please go git &#8216;em!</p><p>The <a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/tools/textile/">test CGI</a> I&#8217;ve created has been updated to use the new code. It&#8217;s a great way to play with the syntax prior to unleashing it on your Movable Type installation.  The <a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/mantis/">Mantis</a> bug tracker is the preferred way to report any bugs you find.</p><p>The beta version of the plugin is <a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/downloads/mttextile-2_0b.zip">available here</a>. But please remember it is a beta release. It may produce &#8220;funky&#8221; results (OK, let&#8217;s not start <em>that</em> again).</p><p>Here&#8217;s a rundown of some of the new syntax:</p><h5>Basic formatting</h5><table cellspacing="0"><tr><th>Technique</th><th>Example</th></tr><tr><td>Style assignment</td><td>p{color:red}. This is a red paragraph.</td></tr><tr><td>Class assignment</td><td>p(first-para). This is the first paragraph.</td></tr><tr><td>Id assignment</td><td>p(#copyright). This is the copyright</td></tr><tr><td>Class/Id</td><td>p(blah#bleh). Class blah, Id bleh.</td></tr><tr><td>Align right</td><td>p&gt;. Align to right</td></tr><tr><td>Align left</td><td>p&lt;. Align left</td></tr><tr><td>Centered</td><td>p=. Align center</td></tr><tr><td>Justified</td><td>p&lt;&gt;. Justified text</td></tr><tr><td>Language assignment</td><td>p[fr]. en Fran&ccedil;aise</td></tr></table><h5>Table Formatting</h5>table{width:400px}=. |\2. This demonstrates a column span. colspan = 2 |-/2. rowspan = 2, vertically centered ||{background-color:yellow}. This shows you can use styles with table cells. |&gt;. With alignment |{background-color:#ccc}|_. Header cell, with row-level style assignment. | *Inline formatting* | And you can evenspan multiple linesnow. |<p>produces&#8230;</p><table cellspacing="0"><tr><td colspan="2">This demonstrates a column span. colspan = 2</td><td valign="middle" rowspan="2">rowspan = 2, vertically centered</td></tr><tr><td>This shows you can use styles with table cells.</td><td align="right" rowspan="1">With alignment</td></tr><tr><th>Header cell, with row-level style assignment.</th><td><strong>Inline formatting</strong></td><td>And you can evenspan multiple linesnow.</td></tr></table><h5>Alignment Characters for Tables</h5><table cellspacing="0"><tr><th align="center">Character</th><th>Alignment</th></tr><tr><td align="center">&gt;</td><td>right</td></tr><tr><td align="center">&lt;</td><td>left</td></tr><tr><td align="center">=</td><td>center</td></tr><tr><td align="center">-</td><td>middle (for vertical alignment)</td></tr><tr><td align="center">^</td><td>align top (like &#8216;sup&#8217; marker)</td></tr><tr><td align="center">~</td><td>align bottom (like &#8216;sub&#8217; marker)</td></tr><tr><td align="center">&lt;&gt;</td><td>justified (align to left and right)</td></tr><tr><td align="center">/n</td><td>Rowspan - n=number (&#8216;/&#8217; reads push downward)</td></tr><tr><td align="center">\n</td><td>Colspan - n=number (&#8216;&#39; reads push forward)</td></tr></table><h5>Footnotes!</h5><p>Example</p>This is an example of a footnote[1].fn1. Here is where the footnote is placed.<p>producing&#8230;</p><p>This is an example of a footnote<sup><a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/001653.php#fn1">1</a></sup>.</p><p><sup>1</sup> Here is where the footnote is placed.</p><h5>Image Alignments</h5><table cellspacing="0"><tr><th align="center">Character</th><th>Alignment</th></tr><tr><td align="center">&gt;</td><td>right (floats right)</td></tr><tr><td align="center">&lt;</td><td>left (floats left)</td></tr><tr><td align="center">-</td><td>inline text, middle/centered</td></tr><tr><td align="center">^</td><td>inline text, align at top</td></tr><tr><td align="center">~</td><td>inline text, align at bottom</td></tr></table><h5>Padding</h5><p>Padding characters are placed with the block markers. Like &#8220;p).&#8221; or &#8220;p(.&#8221;. You can also repeat and mix them as desired: &#8220;p(()).&#8221; means to pad 2em on both the left and right sides.</p><table cellspacing="0"><tr><th align="center">Character</th><th>Meaning</th></tr><tr><td align="center">(</td><td>Pad on left side (1em for each)</td></tr><tr><td align="center">)</td><td>Pad on right side (1em for each)</td></tr></table><h5>Spans</h5>%this is a span%<p>and</p>%(class#id)this span has a CSS class and id%<h4>Putting it all together</h4><p>Here&#8217;s an example of how you can do a lot of formatting with a little bit of Textile:</p>&lt;div style=&quot;width:350px&quot; class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;table)&gt;. |!/photos/summer2003/DSCN0814.thumb.jpg 75% (Georgia Choate)!||=. &lt;small&gt;_My wife, Georgia_&lt;/small&gt;|Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit. Sed sed odio amauris tincidunt consectetuer. Maecenas libero. Lorem ipsum dolor sitamet, consectetuer adipiscing elit. Praesent rhoncus est sit amet augue.Ut non libero. Aliquam mollis eros eu purus. In hac habitasse plateadictumst. Fusce nulla elit, blandit ac, hendrerit quis, sollicitudin eget,enim. Integer sit amet eros ut risus convallis auctor. Duis tortor.Integer imperdiet dignissim neque.&lt;/div&gt;<p>Which produces:</p><table cellspacing="0"><tr><td><img height="112" src="http://www.bradchoate.com/photos/summer2003/DSCN0814.thumb.jpg" width="84"></td></tr><tr><td align="center"><em>My wife, Georgia</em></td></tr></table><p>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit. Sed sed odio a mauris tincidunt consectetuer. Maecenas libero. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit. Praesent rhoncus est sit amet augue. Ut non libero. Aliquam mollis eros eu purus. In hac habitasse platea dictumst. Fusce nulla elit, blandit ac, hendrerit quis, sollicitudin eget, enim. Integer sit amet eros ut risus convallis auctor. Duis tortor. Integer imperdiet dignissim neque.</p><h4>And briefly</h4><p>A quick note to <a href="http://www.dashes.com/anil/">those</a> that wonder why all the fuss. Dean set out to create a kind of shorthand for composing for the web. To be able to write and format your writing with less fuss. Textile is not a replacement for HTML, but complimentary to it. Textile allows you to include HTML and use it&#8217;s shorthand in the same space. But for most things you write, you can probably avoid hitting those &#8220;&lt;&#8221; and &#8220;&gt;&#8221; keys altogether.</p></p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/001649.php">Whither MT-Textile 2?</a></p><p><p>In case you were wondering, MT-Textile 2-point-oh is sort of on hold.</p><p>Don&#8217;t worry &#8212; I have a very good reason.</p><p>Dean Allen (yes, <a href="http://www.textism.com/">that Dean Allen</a>) and I are collaborating on the new features. That is, I&#8217;ve shown him what I added and he&#8217;s suggesting back some additions and changes. We go back and forth refining and improving.</p><p>So it&#8217;s in a bit of flux at the moment. But let me tell you&#8230; the result of all this will be amazing. And best of all, it will have Dean&#8217;s blessing. I made the mistake of improving on Textile with MT-Textile 1.0 and I didn&#8217;t want to make that mistake again with 2.0. The 2.0 syntax I was adding was deepening that rift, to the point that it would be harmful to keep calling it Textile. But now that we&#8217;re working together and defining a common syntax, it will be better for everyone. I just don&#8217;t envy Dean&#8217;s work of doing the 2.0 improvments in PHP. I think Perl is just a little easier at implementing regex.</p><p>In the past few days, we have added:</p><ul><li>Style definition. You can provide style attribute assignments to paragraph, list, image and table elements.</li><li>Alignments. You can specify alignment for paragraph, table and image elements.</li><li>Table improvments. You can now identify rowspan in addition to colspan. Cell data can be written on multiple lines. You can even place lists inside table cells.</li><li>Footnotes.</li></ul><p>I&#8217;ve been incrementally adjusting the Perl Textile code as we&#8217;ve been fleshing out the syntax so it&#8217;s still close to release, but unfortunately is going back to internal testing. The updates have added another zillion test cases to think about. Then it will return to beta for another round of tests. (Sorry to do this to those of you that have helped with the beta testing thus far.)</p><p>The Perl implementation of Textile will be capable of producing HTML (with or without CSS), XHTML 1.x and tenatively XHTML 2 output. The MT-Textile wrapper for the Textile module will continue to tie to <a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/smartypants/">SmartyPants</a> and adds support for <a href="http://mt-plugins.org/archives/entry/codebeautifier.php">MT-CodeBeautifier</a> for formatting code excerpts.</p><p>With all the improvements, Textile is going to be better than ever. I appreciate Dean&#8217;s willingness to work with me on this, since it&#8217;s his baby.</p></p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/001639.php">A Non-Funky MT RSS 2 Template</a></p><p><p>Here&#8217;s my <a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/001639.php">shot</a> at a non-funky RSS 2 template for Movable Type.</p>&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;&lt;$MTPublishCharset$&gt;&quot;?&gt;&lt;rss version=&quot;2.0&quot;&gt;&lt;channel&gt;&lt;title&gt;&lt;$MTBlogName remove_html=&quot;1&quot; encode_xml=&quot;1&quot;$&gt;&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link&gt;&lt;$MTBlogURL$&gt;&lt;/link&gt;&lt;description&gt;&lt;$MTBlogDescription remove_html=&quot;1&quot; encode_xml=&quot;1&quot;$&gt;&lt;/description&gt;&lt;language&gt;en-us&lt;/language&gt;&lt;managingEditor&gt;&lt;MTEntries lastn=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;$MTEntryAuthorEmail$&gt;&lt;/MTEntries&gt;&lt;/managingEditor&gt;&lt;copyright&gt;Copyright &lt;$MTDate format=&quot;%Y&quot;$&gt;&lt;/copyright&gt;&lt;lastBuildDate&gt;&lt;MTEntries lastn=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;$MTEntryDate language=&quot;en&quot;    format=&quot;%a, %d %b %Y %H:%M:%S &quot;$&gt;&lt;$MTBlogTimezone    no_colon=&quot;1&quot;$&gt;&lt;/MTEntries&gt;&lt;/lastBuildDate&gt;&lt;pubDate&gt;&lt;$MTDate language=&quot;en&quot;    format=&quot;%a, %d %b %Y %H:%M:%S &quot;$&gt;&lt;$MTBlogTimezone    no_colon=&quot;1&quot;$&gt;&lt;/pubDate&gt;&lt;generator&gt;http://www.movabletype.org/?v=&lt;$MTVersion$&gt;&lt;/generator&gt;&lt;webMaster&gt;&lt;MTEntries lastn=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;$MTEntryAuthorEmail$&gt;&lt;/MTEntries&gt;&lt;/webMaster&gt;&lt;ttl&gt;60&lt;/ttl&gt;&lt;MTEntries lastn=&quot;15&quot;&gt;&lt;item&gt;&lt;title&gt;&lt;$MTEntryTitle remove_html=&quot;1&quot; encode_xml=&quot;1&quot;$&gt;&lt;/title&gt;&lt;description&gt;&lt;$MTEntryExcerpt encode_xml=&quot;1&quot;$&gt;&lt;/description&gt;&lt;guid isPermaLink=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;$MTEntryPermalink encode_xml=&quot;1&quot;$&gt;&lt;/guid&gt;&lt;category&gt;&lt;$MTEntryCategory remove_html=&quot;1&quot; encode_xml=&quot;1&quot;$&gt;&lt;/category&gt;&lt;pubDate&gt;&lt;$MTEntryDate language=&quot;en&quot;    format=&quot;%a, %d %b %Y %H:%M:%S &quot;$&gt;&lt;$MTBlogTimezone    no_colon=&quot;1&quot;$&gt;&lt;/pubDate&gt;&lt;/item&gt;&lt;/MTEntries&gt;&lt;/channel&gt;&lt;/rss&gt;<p><ins>Updated to remove the link element. Thanks, Mark!</ins></p><p>You&#8217;ll need to use a later version of Movable Type for this &#8212; 2.51 or so I think since it uses &lt;$MTPublishCharset$&gt;. It doesn&#8217;t rely on any externally defined modules &#8212; neither <a href="http://web.resource.org/rss/1.0/modules/dc/">Dublin Core</a> or UserLand&#8217;s <a href="http://backend.userland.com/blogChannelModule">blogChannel module</a>. If you want them, feel free to add that to this.</p><p>This will produce a feed that uses excerpts &#8212; if you want a &#8220;full&#8221; feed that provides the entire content of your post, change the &lt;description&gt; tag to this:</p>&lt;description&gt;&lt;$MTEntryBody encode_xml=&quot;1&quot;$&gt;    &lt;$MTEntryMore encode_xml=&quot;1&quot;$&gt;&lt;/description&gt;<p>The <a href="http://www.thereisnocat.com/funkidator/">Funkidator</a> says this is still not un-funky, because it will use XML CDATA blocks when necessary. That&#8217;s being a little too strict though, since Dave has given his blessing to other feeds that have CDATA blocks even though he doesn&#8217;t use them himself. (<a href="http://www.thereisnocat.com/">Ralph Brandi</a> thinks I&#8217;m taking all this <a href="http://www.thereisnocat.com/showme490.html">much, much too seriously</a>.)</p><p>This is similar to the template I use for my <a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/rss2.xml">RSS 2.0 feed</a>. Of course, it is valid, both by Mark and Sam&#8217;s <a href="http://feeds.archive.org/validator/check?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.bradchoate.com%2Frss2.xml">validator</a> and <a href="http://aggregator.userland.com/validator?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.bradchoate.com%2Frss2.xml">UserLand&#8217;s</a>.</p><p>But the <strong>real</strong> RSS 2.0 Validator &#8212; namely <a href="http://www.scripting.com/">Dave Winer</a> &#8212; will have to let me know if I&#8217;ve got it right.</p><p>Of course, we could just scrap it all and <a href="http://diveintomark.org/archives/2003/06/23/a_fresh_start.html">start over</a>. Sam Ruby is <a href="http://intertwingly.net/wiki/pie/RoadMap">leading the way</a> for defining a new weblog format. There is merit to doing exactly that. If it means putting the past and grievances behind, shaking hands and reaching agreement, then let&#8217;s do it.</p><p>As for a <a href="http://intertwingly.net/wiki/pie/NameIt">name</a>, I think I like <a href="http://intertwingly.net/wiki/pie/NameItPieDiscussion">Pie</a> best of all. It works on many levels:</p><ul><li>Since it is a word, you can consider it as just a name for the syndication format &#8212; it wouldn&#8217;t have to be an acronym.</li><li>If you like acronyms, how about some already suggested: &#8220;Publishing Interface and Exchange&#8221; or &#8220;Public Information Exchange&#8221;.</li><li>As a TLA, it works well for a file extension.</li><li>It describes something consumable, which fits well with syndicated content &#8212; something people consume.</li><li>Would make for a great visual icon. I can see the buttons already. (And they wouldn&#8217;t even need to be orange.)</li><li>The visual image of a piece of pie fits well with the concept of a slice of content &#8212; such as headlines and excerpts from a resource.</li><li>&#8220;Easy as pie&#8221; &#8212; a well known phrase that hopefully speaks to the simple nature of the <a href="http://intertwingly.net/wiki/pie/SyntaxConsiderations">forthcoming format</a>.</li><li>Who doesn&#8217;t like pie?</li></ul><p><ins>Looks like they&#8217;ve settled on Echo. Oh well. Guess that works too.</ins></p></p><hr /><p><a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/past/001645.php">MT-Regex 1.7 Beta</a></p><p><p>A new release for MT-Regex is available for public beta testing. Adds some goodies like grep, split and join. Login to <a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/mantis">Mantis</a> to get it. The news page there has the link to download it.</p></p></td></tr></table>